Mobile No.: +254 706651244, +254 707479567 | Email: **moha.salano@gmail.com** P.O Box 45484 (00100), Nairobi, Kenya | LinkedIn: Ali Salano Mohamed

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

I am an articulate efficient professional with over two-year post graduate experience in knowledge and information management.

My main career objective is to be part of a team that aims and works towards improving its core operations with the intention of making a difference, adding value and enhancing growth.

## **SKILLS AND COMPETENCE**

- A big picture mentality.
- Adaptability and Team player
- Excellent interpersonal and communication skills
- Networking and influencing skills.
- ICT and project management skills.
- Analytical, critical decision making and organization skills.
- Cross functional business skills.
- MS Office suite.

## **EDUCATION**

- B.Sc. Information Science (Records Management and Information Technology)
  Kenyatta University. Second Class Honors (Upper Division) 2018.
- Certificate in Leadership Development and Mentorship (Credit 1) 2018
- Cisco Certified Networking Associate CCNA (Routing & Switching) 2017.
- Pumwani Boys' Secondary School. K.C.S.E Certificate. (2013).

### PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIP

Kenya Association of Records Managers and Archivists. KARMA/0922

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Jan 2021 TO Present - Public Service Commission - Secretariat (P.S.C)

#### Position: Registry and Records Management officer - Intern

- Dealing with enquiries and requests for information from both internal and external clients
- Ensure good records keeping practices and security of data

- filing, classification and data entry into the system
- Archiving of finished files and records
- Developing, maintaining, verifying and evaluating existing systems

#### July 2019- Dec 2019: Kenya Electricity Generating Company Plc. (KenGen)

## Position: Knowledge Management and Innovation officer - Apprentice

- Manage company's library, records and archives to retain company knowledge.
- Enhanced access and first retrieval by digitalization of corporate documents, Information indexing and abstracting.
- Knowledge mapping, collection and documentation of tacit knowledge and sharing to remain competitive.
- Facilitate reorganization of registries operations

### Jan 2019- June 2019: KENYA REVENUE AUTHORITY (K.R.A)

### Position: Knowledge and Records Management Intern

- Create awareness to user departments on records management guidelines (policies, legislative and statutory requirements and standards related to records management)
- Assist user departments in addressing non-conformities raised on control of documented information during previous QMP audits to comply with QMP ISO 9001:2015
- Conduct records survey and appraisal to identify records that have outlived their usefulness and are deemed fit for disposal
- Facilitate reorganization of registries operations and establishing where none exists
- Liaise with user departments to ensure that good housekeeping practice is maintained in storage areas.
- Ensure security of records and information to enhance confidentiality

Sept 2018 to Dec 2018: MICROLAN SOLUTIONS LTD

## **Position: ICT Sales Executive**

- Increased prospects by profiling to identify new potentials and discuss needs with IT managers and propose for solutions so as to increase sales.
- Prepare and submit budget estimates for specific business operation area.
- Analyzing historical sale trend to plan future projection and sale target.

## 2017: Independent Elections and Boundaries Commission Kenya (I.E.B.C)

## **Position: Data Entry Clerk**

- Contributed to team effort by accomplishing voting results as needed.
- Maintained voter confidence by keeping information confidential.
- Use Biometric Voter Registration kits to register voters and conduct elections.

## 2017 May- 2017 August: Department of Immigration & Citizen Services Kenya

## Position: Registry and Records Management Intern

- Ensured availability of information by good file management, electronic file tracking and securing of documents.
- Improved service delivery by fast access, retrieve and return worked on files to the institution registry.
- Good customer relations, by receiving and issuing passports, permits, foreign affairs and visa documents which enhanced efficiency.

## **REFEREES**

### Mrs. Philomena Mumbi.

Supervisor Records and Knowledge Management,

Kenya Revenue Authority,

P. O. Box 48240 – 00100.

Cell no: +254 721145741.

Email: mumbimbuba@gmail.com

### Dr. Harriet Kamau.

Lecturer Department of Library and Information Science,

Kenyatta University,

P.O Box: 43844-00100. Cell no: +254 722581054.

Email: harriet.kamau@ku.ac.ke

## Mr. Joseph Mbugua.

Chief Knowledge Officer.

Kenya Electricity Generating Company,

P.O Box: 47936-00100. Cell no: +254 725974812

Email: josmbugua@kengen.co.ke